You have oil and gas but they go to
У вас есть нефть газ но они уходят в
Moscow And I will say Yes even
Москву И я скажу Да даже даже
when your guys somewhere in sports Yes they
когда Ваши ребята где-то по спорту Да
will take some when how do they do
возьмут какое-то когда как они делают
if someone beat someone in Moscow they
если кто-то кого-то побил в Москве они
beat this Dagestani Yes there is some Yes
этот дагестанец побил Да там какой-то Да
fu And when he stole he And when in sports
фу А когда он украл он А когда в спорте
yes a Dagestani in freestyle wrestling or
да дагестанец по вольной борьбе или ещё
somewhere else they occupy they
где-то занимают они вот российский
say Russian sports True when something is
спортс говорят Правда когда что-то
bad so horses finger thousands Dagestani
плохое так кони пальцем тыщ дагестанец
Yes when something is good it is not a
Да когда что-то хорошее это не
Dagestani it is a Russian athlete they
дагестанец это российский спортсмен они
have
так делали
always done this Hello
всегда Здравствуйте Здравствуйте
Hello Hello
Здравствуйте Вы
Where are you from I hope now we will have a good
откуда Надеюсь сейчас с вами хорошо
just talk and everything is possible because yes
просто побеседуем и всё можно ведь да вы
where are you from Russia the Republic of Mordovia
откуда из России республика Мордовия
Saransk oh-oh-oh
Саранск ай-ай-яй
that my father is Er and my mother is Moksha
что у меня отец Эр и мама мокша
oh-oh-oh so I just when I
ай-ай-яй так что я просто я когда
meet I when Russians Yes I ask
встречаю Я когда россиян Да спрашиваю
they say Who is my nationality
они говорят Кто по национальности меня
I say I say half Erzi
говорю я говорю наполовину эрзи
half Moksha they are like that I say
наполовину мокша они такие что я говорю
in short  you have such a nationality
короче это у вас типа народность такая
in this well in the Republic of Mordovia well
есть в это ну в Республике Мордовия это
they many don't know many don't
ну они такие многие не знают многие не
even understand And what
понимают даже А ты кто по
nationality are you Mard well Tur or Moksha
национальности мард ну тур или мокша
Moksha Moksha I understood and father and mother
мокша мокша понял и отец и мать
Moksha mother Belarusian dad Moksha but you
мокша мама белорусска папа мокша а язык
don't know the language already
не знаешь уже
yes I used to know this like until I was 14 Well
да раньше знал это типа лет до 14 по Ну
re it turns out I have a similar situation it turns out
ре вот у меня схожая ситуация получается
my father and mother already they
у меня отец и мать уже они получается
spoke almost everything in Russian And the
говорили почти всё на русском Да и
child when they were here in the
ребёнка вот когда они были тут в
Soviet Union I was born in the Soviet
Советском Союзе я родился в Советском
Union back in Kyiv They studied here it
Союзе ещё в Киеве Они тут учились
turns out And then we met and
получается И тут познакомились и
stayed after the collapse of the Soviet Union
остались после развала Советского Союза
and it turns out I don't know the Mordvin language at
и я получается вот Мордовский язык не
all unfortunately no well a beautiful
знаю вообще к сожалению не ну красивый
language in fact very Yeah nice
язык на самом-то деле очень Угу приятный
And you what are you studying What do you
А ты ты кем учишься Кем
work as I have two jobs and I'm studying to be a
работаешь имею две работы и учусь на
land surveyor Cool yeah And
землеустроителя Прикольно да А работаешь
what field do you work in
В какой сфере
e seller cashier Well this is at Magnit and cop
э продавец кассир Ну это в Магните и коп
sales
продажи
cryptocurrency Well quite a versatile
криптовалюта Ну довольно разносторонний
person I will say
человек я скажу
Yes I
Да
understand It's interesting and Listen what do you
понял Интересно а Слушай а как
think about what is going on now
относишься к тому идёт сейчас
fratricidal war
братоубийственной война
RZN and Makshan well Erzin and Makshan yes well that
рзн и макшан ну эрзин и макшан да ну то
is our peoples Erzya Moksha Yes who
есть наши народы эрзя мокша Да которые
live both in Russia and in Ukraine Yes
живут и в России и в Украине Да потому
because in the Soviet Union they mixed Yes
что в Советском Союзе перемешивали Да
now they take Erzya and Moksha from Mordovia and
сейчас берут эрзя и мокша из Мордовии и
throw them to fight in Ukraine so that they
бросают их воевать в Украину чтобы они
fight with the Ermi Iksha who live in Ukraine it is
воевали с эрми икшами которые в Украине
very deplorable this is us and so few
живут очень плачевно это нас и так мало
are left you understand the
осталось понимаешь
language is dying dying People and how are you there
умирает язык умирает Народ а как вы там
like well you have some kind of rallies Maybe
типа ну вы чтото какие-то митинги Может
in Saransk they did or what or
в Саранске делали или что или
Deaf like I am not Saransk like sometimes
Глухо типа я не саранс типа иногда
I come there so clean And the city itself I
Приезжаю туда так чисто А сам город
don’t know any rallies maybe there were but
не знаю никаких митингов может были но
like I have never been there That is you
типа меня там ни разу не было То есть вы
as a people have come to terms with the fact that
получается как народ смирились с тем что
yes you are being sent to die in
да вас отправляют умирать в
Ukraine Well most of the guys themselves go
Украину Ну большинство пацанов сами идут
themselves sign the
сами подписывают
contract Well yes But it turns out they are not
контракт Ну да Но получается их же не от
going for a good reason like from a good life
этого от хорошей жизни они идут
Moscow how do they do Moscow takes
Москва как делат Москва забирает
all the Mordovians my father too
мордовские все вот у меня отец тоже
told when he says look Mordvins are the
рассказывал когда говорит смотри Мордва
richest people there and there are resources and
богатейший народ там и ресурсы есть да и
forests and everything yes Moscow takes everything for itself and
лес и всё да Москва забирает всё себе и
has taken everything for itself since time immemorial Yes and
спокон веков забирала всё себе Да а
left Yes and took people as well
оставляла Да и забирала людей также да
yes and trouble Trouble And how do you generally think
да и беда Беда А как ты вообще считаешь
why this whole war began
из-за чего эта вся война началась
under the rule of other countries once
под правлением других стран ещ
again other countries simply sent
раз другие страны просто направили
America America forced Putin to attack
Америка Америка заставила Путина напасть
Ukraine No why why
на Украину Нет почему почему Америка нас
did America force us Well Putin attacked Ukraine yes
заставил Ну напал же Путин на Украину да
then America it forced Putin to pass
то Америка она заставила Путина на пас
or what no yours not
или что нет ваши не
yours like I don't have anything like against
ваши типа я ничего типа не имею против
but Ukrainian infantry fighting vehicles first drove into
но украинские БМП заехали сперва на
Russian territory Ukrainian infantry fighting vehicles where
территорию России украинские БМП куда
they
они
drove I don't remember exactly but on the twenty-
заехали Точно не помню но двадцать
third at 6:00 in the morning So what happened to
третье число в 6:00 утра Так и что с
these infantry fighting vehicles what did they do Where they
этими БМП что они сделали Там где они
drove honestly I don't remember but I
заехали честно не помню но их
just
просто
understood them Well I like it you know it's just a
понял Ну мне нравится зна это просто
brother of
братье
all Well I myself will soon leave under contract
всех Ну я сам по контракту уйду скоро
why well and who else
зачем ну а а кто другой
will go I don't
пойдёт не
know Well why do you want to
знаю Ну а зачем тебе за что ты хочешь
die for your
умереть за
Motherland for For loved ones for people dear to me
Родину за За близких за дорогих мне
so that  they slept peacefully
чтобы они спокойно
You probably don't know how it is And who of your
ты не знаю как это А кто у тебя из
relatives sleeps poorly because you are not
родных плохо спит из-за того что ты не
someone in Ukraine I mean sleeps poorly
кого-то в Украине в смысле плохо спит за
because they will Sleep poorly if there are
что они будут Плохо спать если будет
flights on them so while you have poured on
прилёты по ним так пока пока вы нали на
Ukraine in general there were nikahs Hello, the deputy
Укра вобще было никах
drove in where the BMP drove in
Прив зам заехали та где заехали БМП
Show me And this fake has long been
Покажи А этот фейк уже давным-давно
dispelled if the BMP drove in they shot the
развеяли если бы заехали БМП расстреляли
BMP and that's it And why are you attacking a country
БМП и всё А зачем вы нападает на страну
when someone else's armored vehicles drove into Russian territory It
когда на территорию России заехала Чужая
seems to me that they are not very
бронетехника это мне кажется не очень
good, this is
хороши это
a thing, and where they
вещь а где
drove in I don't remember the truth I just don't remember
заехала я не помню правду не помню
Oh well then let's not do
Да ладно тогда давай не будем
this all the best those Save I
этой все хорошего те Спаси Желаю тебе
wish you I wish you if you go like to s so that it's
желаю тебе если пойдёшь типа на с чтоб
faster let's
побыстрее
talk about the World Cup
давай а ЧМ общаетесь
Well, I just want to talk about something What republic are you from?
Ну разном просто хочется о чём-то Вы из
Republics I am not from a
республики Республики Я не из
republic I live in a city Who by
республики Я в городе живу Кто по
nationality do
национальности
you live in what city is an
в каком городе живёшь
Armenian
армянин
Krasnodar is Armenia or where
Краснодар это Армения или где
is Russia
это Россия
And how Well  you are Armenian then you are
А как Ну ты армянин то Ты
Russian no well you live in Russia Well yeah well
русский нет ну ты в России живешь Ну да
you are
ну Ты
Russian no Armenian is someone who lives in Armenia
русский нет армени это тот кто в Армении
no And who lives in Armenia then
живёт нет А кто в Армении живёт тогда
Azerbaijanis or what
азербайджанцы что ли
Azerbaijanis in Azerbaijan Armenians in
азербайджанцы в Азербайджане армяне в
Armenia Russians in Russia no no no There is no
Армении русские в России нет нет нет Там
such order that
нету такого распорядка то что в России
Russians live in Russia Armenians live in Armenia no
живут русские в Армении живут армяне нет
Who lives in Who lives in A in
Кто живёт в Кто живёт в А в
Armenia Well there are many different Well
Армении Ну там есть много разных Ну
like A well Armenians live in Armenia Yes
типа А ну в Армении живут армяне Да в
Russians live in Russia Yeah right ru
России живут русские Да ну
Dudes Tatars live there and then there are
ру Там живут чуваки
Chechens no Wait
татары дальше ещ чеченцы не Подожди
look Russians live in Russia in Ukraine
смотри в России живут русские в Украине
Ukrainians in France French in Armenia
украинцы во Франции французы в Армении
Armenians in Turkey Turks like well that's it Well then
армяне в Турции турки типа ну всё Ну то
you are Russian since you are in Russia Me and Dad they
ты русские раз ты в России ме с папо они
moved to Russia well and Russian Well then you are
переехали в Россию ну и русский Ну то Ты
Russian no you have a
русский нет у тебя паспорт
Russian passport I don't have a passport Well the
русский У меня нету паспорта Ну
birth certificate is Russian And what Well
свидетельство рождени русское И что Ну
then you are Russian
то ты
Okay then if by your
русский Окей значит если по вашей
logic
логике
an Armenian is born in Ukraine or there
армянин родится в Украине или там
an Azerbaijani Ukrainian pass no Wait
азербайджанец украинец пас не Подождите
he has there in  it will be written in the passport
у него там в паспорте будет написано то
that he is an Azeri by nationality in our
что вот он по нации Азер у нас в
passport there is no such nationality at all in
паспорте в паспорте нету вообще этого
my passport I have a friend yes look
у меня У меня знакомый есть да смотри у
I have a friend he is himself his parents
меня знакомый он сам его родители из
came from Yerevan he was born here he is
Еревана приехали он тут Родился он
Ukrainian And you are
украинец А ты
Russian What nonsense Well how Well you
русский Что за бред Ну как Ну ты в
live in Russia You are
России живёшь Ты
Russian a nation a nation is the blood of a
русский нация нация это это кровь
people sh
народа шь
blood my ancestors are Armenians all my
кровь у меня предки армяне у меня все
ancestors are Armenians So I have something
предки армяне Значит у меня что-то
Armenian wait Where are you from not like you
армянский подожди Откуда ты не как ты
blood Maybe these are not your ancestors you
кровь Ты может это не твои предки
understand You don't know blood you haven't
понимаешь Ты же не знаешь кровь ты Не
measured
мерил
blood blood Well what kind of
кровь кров Ну
logic is that Hugo This is
какте что там Уго за логика такая Это
nonsense You are just some kind of blood Well you
бред Просто ты какой-то кровь Ну ты
live in Russia You are Russian Russia I am not
живёшь в России Ты русский Раша Я не
Russian Russian you Well who are you
русский русский ты Ну а кто ты
Russia Armenians Armenians are those who
России армени армяне - это те кто в
live in Armenia
Армении живут
No why do you have such logic why
Нет почему у вас такая логика почему
such Let's do it Who lives in
такая Давай так Кто живёт в
Poland Poles Who lives in Armenians in
Польше поляки Кто живёт в армяни в
Armenia Armenians Who lives in
Армении армяни Кто живёт в
Russia Russia Yes you are Russian
России Россия Да ты русский
Russian damn you know Well look in Poland
россиянин блин знаете Ну смотри в Польше
Poles in Armenia Armenians in Russia Russians
поляки в армени армяне в России русские
So did you know And did you know that in Russia
Так вы знали А вы знали то что в России
lives how many 60 or 70% of Russians live there
живёт вот сколько там 60 или 70% живёт
that is these 30% they they are there
русских то есть эти 30% они они там
Dudes
Чуваки
Tajiks Armenians these in short Russia - that
таджики армяне эти короче Россия - это
is in your opinion wait you want to
же то есть по вашему подожди ты хоче
say that Russia is like a country of
скать что Россия как бы страна
everyone yes Russia is a multinational
всех да Россия - это многонациональная
country a multinational country that is
страна многонациональная рана то есть
Armenia is a country of Armenians Ukraine is
Армения - это страна армян Украина
a country of Ukrainians Poland is a country of Poles and
страна украинцев Польша страна Поляков а
Russia is a country of
Россия - это страна
everyone
всех
Don't look I can't understand Russia is a
Не смотрите Не могу понять Россия - это
multinational country but more
многонациональная страна но там больше
Russians live there I guess And whose Crimea is by the way how do
живёт русский поди А чей Крым кста как
you think
ты счита
Russian
руский
Russian Russian Crimea And you are Russian Well
российский русский Крым А ты русский Ну
and you are Russian it turns out I am not everything as you
и ты русский получается я не всё как вы
defined it Well if Crimea Well look
это определили Ну если Крым Ну смотри
if you say that Crimea is
если ты говоришь что Крым
Russian Russia is multinational but Crimea is
русский Россия многонациональная но Крым
Russian Well then you are also Russian you are in
русский Ну значит ты тоже русский ты в
Russia Crimea in Russia you are in Russia you are
России Крым в России ты в России вы
Russians look That is if I would
русские смотрите То есть если бы я бы
say that Crimea is Turkey it turns out I
сказал то что Крым Турции это получается
would be a Turk no no It's just that I well you
был бы турком нене Просто я ну е ты
say that no said Crimea  Iran
говоришь что нет сказал Крым Ирана
then I am Iranian let's do it Krasnodar
значит я иранец давай так Краснодар
Russian Krasnodar Russian Yes And you live
русский Краснодар русский Да И ты живёшь
in
в
Krasnodar Well then You are
Краснодаре Ну значит Ты
Russian well your mother who is Ukrainian by nationality
русский хорошо у вас мама кто по нации
And your father is
украинка А папа
Ukrainian Look if you move to
украинец Смотрите если вы переедет в
some other country So then in
какую-то другую страну Так значит по
fact cheat in fact you will no longer be that
факту чит по факту вы уже не будете той
Nazi who is Well yes if I poison in France
наци кото есть Ну да если яду во Франции
my children will be French Well of course
дети мои будут французами Ну конечно
if I live in Armenia and the children will be
если я в Армении буду жить и дети будут
Armenians
армянами
will
будут
trolled Popik yes yes And where
затроллил Попик да да А ты откуда
are you from Where are you from
будешь Ты откуда будешь
Dagestan Dagestan Avar Kumyk Lak
Дагестан Дагестан аварец кумык лакец
Tabasaran Dargin
табасаранец даргинец
Avar like Imam Shamil handsome
аварит как Имам Шамиль красавчики
yes What are you talking about now IC in the chat I
да О чём Сейчас общаетесь ИК в чате вот
wanted to talk to Ukrainians they immediately
хотел с украинцами разговаривать сразу
start scolding insulting I don't know what
начинают ругать оскорблять Я не знаю что
so And what is this white thing on your table g g
так А что у вас белое на столе такое г г
Wow and this is a drawing Yes I understood us at the
Вот это да а это рисунок Да нас на
lecturer I understood how you feel about the fact
лекторе понял понял как относитесь тому
that Russia attacked Ukraine
что Россия напала на Украину
necessity
необходимость
necessity there is such an interesting
необходимость есть вот такой интересный
question Are you an Avar do you revere Imam
вопрос Вы авар почитаете Имама
Shamil yes And how does it happen that  Imam
Шамиля да А как так получается что Имам
Shamil fought against the Russians Yes And
Шамиль боролся против русских Да А вы
now you've been holding the dogs down for
сейчас прижим собакам
25 years, destroyed 70% of the Avars and lost to the
25 лет уничтожил 70% аварцев и проиграл
Russians and then told us, the Russians,
русским и сказал потом нам русскими
Live in peace We must be friends with them, we
Живите дружно С ними надо дружить с ними
can't fight with them If we fight with them, it
воевать нельзя Если с ним воевать нам
will be really bad for us, we won't exist at all And since
вообще плохо будет нас вообще не будет И
then we've been living with Russia and
вот с тех по с росси живём и хорошо
living well, yes, that is, then these are
живём да то есть тогда ж вот это войска
Yermolov's troops, they are your grandparents, all
Ермолова они ваших бабушек дедушек всех
of your ancestors Yes And now you're kind of
из ваших предков Да А вы сейчас типа
smiling, well, baby, tell me, if
улыбаетесь вот ээ малыш скажи вот если
your dad were a Russian soldier, would you
бы твоего папу Русский солдат ты бы
love the Russians for
русских любил за
this No Well, your dad loves the Russians,
это Нет Во а твой папа любит русских
you see, because pride has disappeared,
видишь потому что гордость пропала
national pride once Yes, there
национальная гордость когда-то Да на
were very proud people in the Caucasus, very
Кавказе были очень гордые люди очень
proud And freedom-loving And now Well,
гордые Да и свободолюбивые А сейчас Да
who are you, just some kind of
ну кто вы просто реально какой-то
appendage of the Russians Yes, they call you chu, yes, they
придаток русских Да они вас чу называют
say they arrived When they arrive Yes,
говорят приехали они Когда приезжают Да
there in Dagestan they're like, Oh, this is our
там в Дагестан они типа О это наша
Russia, yes And when you arrive in Moscow, you've
Россия да А когда вы приедете в Москву
come in droves, as they write on the Internet
понаехали как они в интернете
I work They treat me very well
пишут работаю Очень хорошо относятся это
This is so there is nothing Tell me tell me
это тако ничего нету Расскажи расскажи
you are just a
ты просто
migrant Work for us and that's it They don't
мигра работа у на на нас и вс они не
respect you and Maloy Look you will grow up
уважают вас и Малой Смотри ты вырастешь
baby Yes where did you go Come on Give the
малыш Да у тебя Куда ушёл Давай Верни
baby back Listen you no no you were embarrassed
малыша Слушай ты не не ты застеснялся
for the little one to listen it's a
чтобы малой слушал
shame Mom came that's why they went and
стыдно ма пришла они поэтому шли а
you are ashamed It's a shame because your son
стыдно тебе Стыдно потому что сын
will grow up and he has two paths yes
вырастет да и у него есть два пути да
two paths to be like this
два пути быть таким
chew clack to them and become the second path to
жевать кла им да и стать второй путь
become a free man Here his
стать свободным человеком Вот его
generation can still wrest freedom for itself
поколение ещё может вырвет себе свободу
Yes and you are sitting Dagestan is the richest
Да а ты сидишь Дагестан богатейший
region
регион
Derbent is just a damn ancient city Yes
Дербент просто блин древнейший город Да
Kaspi has oil there and you are sitting there teeth
Каспи есть нефть туда а ты сидишь зубы
no even why do all Muscovites have
даже нет почему у москвичей у всех зубки
good teeth Yes because Muscovites take
хорошие Да потому что москвичи забирают
money from Avars from Chechens from Dargins from
деньги у аварцев у чеченцев у даргинцев
Kumyks Yes it takes from everyone
у кумыков Да у всех Забирает да
and that's why you and them for pennies to
и поэтому те ты иь к ним за копейки
work they still don't
работать они тебя ещ не
respect you I read you I don't you  respect
уважают читаю тебя я тебя не уважаю
Because you don't respect yourself you
Потому что ты сам себя не уважаешь ты
bow down to the Russians Yes you have humiliated
преклоняется перед русскими Да ты унизил
yourself your family and yours You are a kafir kafir
себя свой род и своих Ты кафиром кафиром
just
просто
class yes
клаес да
Ari Shame shame of the Avar people shame of the
Ари Позор позор аварского народа позор
Avar
аварского
people you shame of the Avar
народа ты позор аварского
people
народа
shame on
позор
You look at your teeth Look at my teeth
по Ты посмотри зубы Посмотри на мои зубы
and look at yours you can't be an adult
и посмотри на твои ты не можешь взрослый
man Yes you can't have normal
мужчина Да не можешь иметь нормальные
teeth Why Because in Russia Yes there is
зубы Почему Потому что в России Да денег
no money Even there is no money they take everything to
нету Даже денег нет они всё забирают в
Moscow yes
Москву да пальце
pick a finger pomery which one Which finger
поковырять померий какой Какой палец
will fit little finger or thumb will fit into this hole
влезет мизинец или большой в эту дырку
Here is a dentistry nearby and
пролезет Вот это рядом стоматология а
next to Tomorrow I will go Yes tomorrow tomorrow
рядом Завтра пойду Да завтра завтра
I will do yes tooth
сделаю да зуба
So you really Yes there are but there are in
Так что вы реально Да есть но есть в
Dagestan Guys yes who still remember
Дагестане Ребята да которые ещё помнят
freedom remember Shamil's Testament and remember what it
свободу помнят Завет Шамиля и помнят что
is to fight against the Russian Empire And
такое борьба против Российской империи А
you just well you became a mankurt you became
вы просто ну ты стал манкурт ты стал
your family your people your ancestors Yes they
свой род свой народ твои предки Да
just spit on the sky now and watch how
просто плюют сейчас небес и смотрят как
our  the seed could have given birth to such a tribe
наше семя могло породить такое племя
you know they look and say how can it
понимаешь смотрят и говорят как может
be we shed blood for our mountains for
быть мы проливали кровь за наши горы за
our family for our children mothers yes and
наш род за наших детей матерей да А
now now they themselves what is your
сейчас сейчас они себя как тебя
name Abdurakhman Abdurakhman mountains AS
зовут Абдурахман Абдурахман гор АС
Abdurakhman sits and everything in short he is just
Абдурахман сидит и всё короче он
like Well you are ashamed too
такой просто Ну тебе стыдно тоже потому
because I am Ukrainian Yes I say we drove out the Russians we
что я украинец Да я говорю мы русских
drove out the Russians yes yes it
прогнали мы прогнали русских да да нам
was hard for us it was hard for us but we never
тяжело было нам тяжело но мы никогда не
bow down And you now instead
преклоняюсь А вы сейчас вместо того
of Yes at least keep silent I understand
чтобы Да хотя бы промолчать Я понимаю
that it is hard for you that there are few of you Yes there are
что вам тяжело что вас мало Да аварцев
slightly more than a million Avars there but no one is
там чуть больше там миллиона но никто ж
pulling your tongue yes Russia Well done And
не тянет вас за язык да Россия Молодцы И
so on Wait for your time look small
так дальше Ждите своего часа смот малень
Estonia million population left the Soviet
Эсто милна населения вышла из Советского
Union Yes Lithuania Estonia how does Estonia
Союза Да Литва Эстония как живёт Эстония
live how does Dagestan live look Dagestan is
как живёт Дагестан посмотри Дагестан
three times larger than Estonia is richer Yes
крупнее в три раза Эстонии богаче Да у
Estonia has nothing at all just
Эстонии вообще ничего нет вообще только
access to the sea
выход к морю
and Latvia is nearby and they live Cool and
да под боком и Латвия и живут Круто а
Dagestan Dagestan has the Caspian Sea there is
Дагестан Дагестан есть Каспи есть неба
oil in the sky  sells gas to Europe sells to
нефть продаёт в Европу газ продаёт в
Europe Azerbaijan and Dagestan has a fig
Европу Азербайджан а Дагестан имеет дулю
fig in Turkic is called fig that's
кукиш кукиш по тюркски называется кукиш
all And if we look at the Azerbaijanis Yes
всё И если мы смотрим азербайджанцы Да
they have an idea on the world stage
они имеют представление на мировой арене
they are respected they know that there is such a people And
их уважают знают что есть такой народ А
look at you Russians don't even know
увас смотри вас русские даже не знают
that there are Avars Dargins Kumyks they are
что есть аварцы даргинцы кумыки они
like that this is something Dagestanis there is something Yes
такие это что-то дагестанцы там такое Да
something like a collection of incomprehensible
что-то такое сборное непонятное
bearded Yes that's all I felt ashamed
бородатое Да вот и всё Стыдно стало
because all sorts of peoples We Ukrainians were also
что всякие народы Мы украинцы тоже были
without our own state for a very long time
без своего государства очень долго
because we were once captured Yes but
потому что когда-то нас захватили Да но
here's the truth I'm telling you Look but we
вот вот се правду говорю Посмотри но мы
restored we The heirs of the Great
восстановили мы Наследники Великой Руси
Kievan Rus Yes and we restored our
Киевской Да и мы восстановили своё
state Yes it was hard yes
государство Да было тяжело да наших Люде
our People were thrown into prisons Yes the Tsarist
кидали в тюрьмы Да наших людей Царская
government Soviet power killed our people Yes but we
власть Советская власть убивала Да но мы
passed and carried proudly proudly because
прошли и пронесли гордо гордо потому что
we Ukrainians are a free people And you are an Avar yes
мы украинцы вольный Народ а Вы авар да
you were once a free people once
вы когда-то были вольный народ когда-то
look Let me say  you come on with
смотри Дай мне говорит ти давай с Давай
Come on say come on Okay Let's talk here I served
скажи давай Окей Поговорим вот я служил
in the Soviet times Soviet army
в советское время Советской армии
Ukrainians
украинцами
served audible audible audible you
служил слышно слышно слышно вас
audible
слышно
audible I hear you but I say I
слышно я тебя слышу а вот я говорю
served 8 days a year Ukrainians served they
служил 8 дено год украинцами служил они
Ukrainians are better this served Russians
украинцы лучше это служили русским им
obeyed them and that's how than
подчинялись и вот так чем
we you say this from Russia Russians
мы ты говоришь это с России русских
were driven out I don't know what you didn't serve there but
выгнали не зна что ты там с не служил но
now we are free in our country we
мы сейчас свободные в своей стране мы
drove out Russians And you bow down they
прогнали русских А вы преклоняется они у
take everything from you Well yes you have oil
вас забирают всё Ну да у вас есть нефть
gas but they go to Moscow And I will say Yes
газ но они уходят в Москву И я скажу Да
even even when your guys somewhere in
даже даже когда э Ваши ребята где-то по
sports Yes they will take some when how do they
спорту Да возьмут какое-то когда как они
do if someone beat someone in
делают если кто-то кого-то побил в
Moscow they beat this Dagestani Yes there
Москве они этот дагестанец побил Да там
some Yes fu And when he stole he
какой-то Да фу А когда он украл он
and when in sports yes Dagestani in
а когда в спорте да дагестанец по
freestyle wrestling or somewhere else
вольной борьбе или ещё где-то занимают
they occupy here Russian athlete say
они вот российский спортсмен говорят
True when something bad like that  they point a
Правда когда что-то плохое так они
finger thousands Dagestani Yes, when something is
пальцем тыщ дагестанец Да когда что-то
good, it is not a Dagestani, it is a Russian
хорошее это не дагестанец это российский
athlete, they have always done this and look,
спортсмен они так делали всегда и смотри
ours are also Ukrainian poets, writers,
наши тоже украинские были поэты писатели
musicians, artists, athletes,
были музыканты художники были спортсмены
they all said it is Russian,
они все говорили это российский
Soviet, that's all,
Советский вот и всё
you have served until now, you
вы служили до сих пор вы
served the Russians, now serve
служили русским тепер служите
the Americans, you have never been
американцам вы никогда не были
independent, we are a free people,
независимыми мы свободный Народ у нас
look, we have our own president, our own
смотри у нас есть свой президент свой
parliament, you do not have your own presidency, we
парламент у вас нет своего прези У нас
have a constitution, a parliament, a president,
есть Конституция парламент президент у
you do not have one, you are nobody, who are you, you are an Avar, you
вас нету вы никто кто Вы авар у вас
do not have a school, you have one
школы нету у
in Ukrainian, children learn everything
есть на украинском языке дети всё учат
in Ukrainian, in our native language, and what do
на украинском на нашей ридне мове А что
you have in Avar, mathematics, physics, no,
у вас на аварском математика физика нету
everything was left to you as the language of the aborigines, once
всё вам оставили как язык аборигенов раз
a week or twice a week, teach a
в неделю или два раза в неделю поучи
child some language that no one
ребёнок какой-то язык который никому не
will need, and then you will go and see this
нужен будет Да ты потом пойдёшь этот
language, it seems like you
язык вроде как
know some interesting language, but it
знаешь какой-то интересный а так нигде
will not be used anywhere, everything, your language
не будет использоваться всё язык ваш
is forgotten, traditions are forgotten,
забывается традиции забываются
Russia simply erases, yes, you, they look
Россия стирает просто да вы они смотрят
at you  like some of those from the zoo
на вас как каких-то таких из зоопарка Да
Well, look there in the mountains some kind of bekho
вот смотрите там в горах какие-то бехо
It's very good that there is Why do we need the
Это очень хорошо что есть зачем нам
Avar language that no one
аварский язык который никто не понимает
understands Everyone understands the Russian language Everyone speaks Russian Everyone
русский язык все понимают на русском все
speaks Ukrainy Everyone speaks English
разговаривают Укра все разговаривают на
and not Russian Everyone
английском а не на русском все на
speaks English But you don't learn
английском говорят но вы не учите потому
Because you don't need Avar So you should
что вас аварский нас не нужен Так вы бы
learn and Avar is your own Yes, that's me
учили и аварский свой да родной Да это я
English And why And I told you You
английский А зачем а я вам сказала вы
will learn and that's it Look earlier Yes
будете учить и всё посмотри раньше да
Earlier How even Tolstoy respected you
Раньше Как вас уважали даже Толстой
wrote Yes, that's why [ __ ] Murad
писал да поэтому там Хаджи Мурад
wrote Yes Lermontov wrote about the
писал писал да Лермонтов писал про
Caucasus warriors And what is Russian now Yes He
Кавказ воины А что сейчас русский Да
writes When they still tried to
пишет когда они ещё пробовали вас
fight You, they respected you Yes, what are you
воевать воевать они уважали Да что вы
warriors Yes And now they write some kind of this They
воины да А сейчас они пишут какие-то это
came here to work at our construction site
Приехали тут поработать у нас на стройке
That's all they treat you like that
вот и всё так они к вам относятся
Janitors Come to us from Dagestan
дворники приедь нам из Дагестана
Couriers Tell us and also also Yes They do
курьеры говори и также тоже да они всех
n't like all non-Russians Uzbeks
всех не русских так не любят узбеки
Tajiks You are all just chu for them Everything for
таджики вы для них все просто чу все для
them is that's what they say  look
них они так и говорят ты посмотри
put an Uzbek next to you and he
поставь возле тебя узбека и тебя он
will tell you what this is and that's
скажет что это за вот и
it You see this child the wife is afraid of the
всё Вот видите этот ребнок жена боится с
Ukrainian does not talk says they are
украинцем не разговаривает говорит они
dangerous people they
опасные люди
say Yes that's
говорят Да
right the wife
правильно жена забрала
took the phone wife give the phone back to the
телефона жена верни телефон
man wife give the
мужчине жена верни телефон
man's phone back he is afraid of Russians and even
мужчины он русских боится а жену ещё
more
больше
afraid of his wife
боится
everything the Avar has come
всё пришла
finish
аварка закончи
once oh al Hello How are you
раз о ал Здравствуйте Как дела
Hello you have a rather interesting
Здравствуйте у вас довольно интересный
face design
фейс дизайн
cool I just work as a stylist I
прикольно Я просто работаю стилистом
appreciated your
Оценил Ваш
Face style hairstyles are quite original
лица причёски рови довольно оригинально
No well I would not say that there is something
Не ну я бы не сказал что ту что-то
original Well there is look You are
оригинально есть Ну есть смотрите Вы оче
very quite high from the general Tol rarity What is
довольно высь из общей Тол редкость Как
your
вас
name My name is Tamirlan
зовут Меня зовут тамирлан
Tamirlan you are a Turk who are you by
тамирлан вы тюрк кто Вы по
nationality I am Ossetian by
национальности я осетин по
nationality Ossetian
национальности осетин
Alan Well the Republic of North Ossetia Yes
Алан Ну Республика Северная Осетия Да я
I am My father is an Ironian from Ossetia too And
я У меня отец иро нец из Осетии тоже А
you are an Iron Digore
ты иро Дигоре
who am I onu I am Ossetian Well well Ossetian Iron rets
кто я ону я осетин Да ну осетин иро рец
Who are you Iron Iron too damn Handsome
Кто ты иро иро тоже ирони блин Красава
bro Where
братан А откуда ты
exactly are you from exactly  I'm from Beslan and Beslan Yes, my
именно я с Беслана а Беслан Да у меня
father is from Khiva, ofi, we are the result, in
отец из Хива родом офи мы оказва вот на
fact, I don't meet any person here,
деле какого я человека тут не встречаю
so either he was in Ossetia some time ago,
так он либо в Осетии был когда-то
or someone is related to him from In short, I'm in
либо кто-то ему доводится из Короче я в
shock Well, look, like the Alans, we were
шоке Ну много смотри типа аланы мы были
settled All over the Black Sea region, this is
расселены По всему причерноморье это же
our Alan territory, yes, yes, yes, that's for
наший территории аланский дадада да это
sure The Great Lania was from the Caspian Sea to
точно Великая лания была от Каспия да до
the Bosphorus, and then wait, it seems like
Босфора а потом подожди вроде бы
some part of the Alans
какая-то часть Алан из-за Великой
migrated to Western Europe due to the Great Migration
миграции в западную Европу перекочевала
Yes, yes, if we look at the Balkan
Да да да если смотрим на балканском
Peninsula Yes, in Croatia
полуострове Да в Хорватии
there is a certain
есть определённая
territory Where the heirs of the Alans live,
территория Где живут Наследники Алана
they have already mixed with the Balkans themselves,
они уже смешались с Балкан сами
but ofi I'm in shock In short, why so many Are
но офи Я в шоке Короче почему так много
punished Well, look, we were
Наказывается Так ну мы смотри мы были
once dominant in these
когда-то господствующие на этих
territories Yes, the Black Sea Scythian
территориях Да причерноморский Скиф
Kiriki, we were the dominant
Кирики мы были господствующим
people, we held tribute to us Well,
народом мы держали на нам Дань
yes Well, by the way, yes, I
платила Ну да Ну кстати да с этим я
can't argue with that  in fact,
поспорить не могу на самом-то деле я
when I meet Russians too I say that
когда русских тоже встречаю Я говорю что
I am Alan otin Yes
я Алан отин Да
they or go Look when you were in
они или го Смотри когда вы были в
the swamps there lived we Ossetians our
болотах там жили мы осетины уже наши
kings already ruled you you know in
цари правили вами знаете знаете вот на
fact it's the
самом-то
same because how the border is translated
льно потому что как переводится граница
That is, for example, to the Tajiks, Kazakhs,
То есть например к таджикам казахам
Uzbeks and all sorts of peoples
узбекам и вот таким всяким народам
who migrated
которые мигрировали
to Russia they can be called because well,
вот в Россию их можно назвать потому что
like from abroad as the Germans
ну типа из-за границы как немцев раньше
were called before Well, the Germans themselves it is because not
называли Ну немцы сами это потому что не
us our ancestors did not understand them Wait and what am
мы мых предки их не понимали Подожди а
I the border And honestly I don't know but I
ского я граница А честно не знаю но я
know that it is so It is translated so that
знаю то что оно так Переводится так что
if an Ossetian from Russia, for example,
если осетин из России например
migrated to Moscow then Well only
перекочевал в Москву то Ну только
Muscovites can call him that
москвичи его так могут называть ну
Well wait wait That is, it turns out that an
подожди подожди То есть получается
Ossetian
осетин
from North Ossetia he does not turn out to be an
из Северной Осетии он не получается
Ossetian from Khiva
осетин из Хива
already Well in fact,
уже ну на самом-то деле
so wait here wait you want to
б так постой тут подожди ты хочешь
say that my father who was born in
сказать что мой отец который родился в
Tskhinvali he is in short chu And you from Beslan
цхинвале он короче чу А ты с Беслана
not here in  I mean, this
не тут имеется в виду как раз таки эта
border, that is, chu, is generally
граница то есть чу вообще это
considered an insult, this is generally such,
оскорбление считается это вообще такие
this word has grown into an insult
это слово переросло в оскорбление
when Well, from Central Russia,
когда Ну из Центральной России
you understand Well, in short, everyone who is not Russian,
понимаете Ну короче все кто не русские
they call it that That's it, but the real
они так называют Вот вот вот а настоящее
meaning of chu is simply a border Well, that's
значение чу это просто граница Ну суть
not the point The point is that
не в том Суть в том что современные вот
these modern Russians Yes, they are Nazis, they call everyone who is
эти русские Да они нацисты они всех кто
not Russian chu I say that we Yes,
не русский называют чу я говорю что мы
we built you the state of Rus' Yes,
Да мы построили вам государство Русь Да
our, uh, tsars Yes, Alanian Ossetian Yes,
наши ээ цари Да аланские осетинские Да
they ruled all of this territory They
они правили все этой территории У них
didn't have writing yet, the Russians, we
ещё письменности у русских не было мы им
brought it to them and that's it Uh-
принесли и всё
huh Well, I can't argue with that
Угу Ну с этим я спорить не
And who are you studying for, who are you
могу а ты кем учишься на кого
working for? I teach I don't work yet I'm
работаешь Я учу я пока не работаю я
studying to be a doctor at
учусь на врача в
Sogma, where where where where Sogma Academy,
согма где где где где согма Академия
such as in the
такая во воде
Caucasus, oh, something's frozen I don't have it,
Кавказе ой что-то зависли у меня нет нет
everything's fine,
всё нормально
but I was thinking And by the way, are you a Streamer
а я задумался А вы кстати Стример
No, I'm an Ossetian
Нет я осетинский
blogger, oh, I'm the most famous Ossetian
блогер офи я самый известный осетинский
blogger in Europe I'm from Brussels myself Yes,
блогер в Европе Я из Брюсселя сам Да
oh, what,
офи А что
Holy [ __ ] Well  you know, you won't
[__] Ну знаете как бы не каждого
meet every person who lives in Brussels
человека встретишь который в Брюсселе
Well, of course, not everyone Yes, more than
живёт Ну да конечно не каждого Да больше
that I'm in Brussels I preach Alania to the whole European Union
того Я в Брюсселе Я на весь Евросоюз
Yes, I tell
проповедуют Алании Да я рассказываю
Europeans that they don't know that
европейцам что они же не знают что там
Ossetians live there in Russia they don't know that
живут осетины в России они не знают что
we are Great Russia Yes, we are
мы и есть Великая Россия Да мы
modern Russia Yes, it's only in the
современная Россия Да она только там в
last centuries that something has gotten out of hand
последние Столетия что-то там выбилась
Yes, and all history, wherever you look, our
да а вся история куда не Гля наши
Alanian Ossetian kings were
аланские осетинские цари были
everywhere, in fact, I didn't
всюду на самом-то
really understand my Well, when
де особо понимал вот свою Ну когда
And before that, how can
А до той поры как
I explain this Well, in short, when I
я как это объяснить Ну короче когда я не
wasn't into politics or history Well, I'm not
увлекался вот политикой историей Ну я не
saying that I'm just an expert I generally
говорю что я прямо специалист Я вообще
thought that Ossetians were such
ну считал осетинов таким
a small people But when I began to
немногочисленным народом Но когда я стал
understand this more or less I remember
в этом разбираться более-менее Я помню
how great my past is, you
насколько у меня великое прошлое да
know, and What do you What do you know about the
понимаешь а Что ты Что ты знаешь про
past, the past, the past, the
прошло оти прошло
past, in fact, nothing so
отин на самом-то деле ничего такого
detailed about Well, I only know about the
подробного про Ну я знаю только про
Alan state that it existed
государство Алан то что оно существовало
and was quite
и было достаточно
[music]
[музыка]
dominant, banal That's by the way,
господствующим банально Вот кстати то то
what
что
I  I
я сейчас в
'm on chatroulette now and almost every
чатрулетке нахожусь и практически каждый
Ukrainian will know something about Ossetia.
украинец что-то про Осетию узнает Вот
This is also one of the
это тоже один из
factors. By the way, can I ask another question?
факторов А кстати можно ещё вопрос
Yes,
задать да
you've been to Ukraine. Well, it's just that
Вы же вы в Украине были Ну просто у вас
you're from Brussels. Brussels or do you
Да вы родом из Брюсселя Брюсселя или
just live there? No, I'm from Crimea. I'm
просто живёте там нет я родом из Крыма я
Crimean Alan, an Ossetian. And in 2014,
Крымский Алан осетин а а в 2014 году
when Russia occupied Crimea, my
когда Россия оккупировала Крым мы с
parents and I left for Brussels.
родителями уехали в Брюссель
Brussels, I understand. So you prefer
брюсель понятно То есть вы предпочитаете
Ukraine. Yes,
Украину да
yes. Well, that's cool.
да Ну прикольно что
What do you
сказать А как вы кстати
think about this conflict? I
относитесь вообще к этому конфликту
support Ukraine in every possible way. We
вообще всячески поддерживаю Украину мы
send weapons here from Europe.
пересылаем тут из Европы оружие
We send donations so that it's
пересылаем донаты для того чтобы
faster. In short, the Armed Forces.
побыстрее короче
In short, Moscow, there, Grozny,
разм ВС короче Москву там короче Грозный
Vladikavkaz, Beslan, everyone. In short, Chechnya,
Владикавказ Беслан всех короче Чечню
Ossetia, everyone. All of Russia should
Осетию всех вот вся Россия должна короче
burn. That's my position. Wait. That
гореть Вот моя позиция такая стойте То
is, you can even list North
есть вы даже перечисляйте северную
Ossetia. The republic in which the
Осетию Республику в которой живут
Ossetians live. Well, yes, because it's Russia, the
осетины Ну да потому что ну это Россия
Russian Federation, if the Ossetians don't
Российская Федерация если осетины не
want them to  they destroyed it should leave the
хотят чтобы их уничтожили они долж выйти
Russian
ста Российской
Federation Well, if it leaves the
Федерации Ну так если она выйдет из
Russian Federation, it will
состава Российской Федерации то будет
only be worse for it Well,
только хуже для неё же самой Ну да
look It's none of my business, you Ossetians
смотри Это ж не моё дело вы осетины сами
must choose yourselves, yes, either leave the
должны выбрать да либо выходите из
Russian Federation, worse, better,
состава Российской Федерации хуже лучше
or so on And you are not being bombed, yes,
или так дальше Да и вас не бомбят да
or you are being bombed, in short, together with the
либо вас бомбят короче вместе с
Russian Federation, everything is simple, it's
Российской Федерацией всё просто это
war Well,
война Ну
honestly, I would understand If you were an Ossetian Well,
честно я бы понял Если бы вы осетин Ну
tell us about everything except North
сказали бы про всё кроме самой Северной
Ossetia itself, let it put it, let it leave the
Осетии пусть её ставит пусть она выедет
composition Well, let it be
из состава Ну пусть её
bombed
разбомбленный
to Ukraine Everything means Ossetia, they are not protesting
в Украину Всё значит Осетия не митингуют
against it, it means Ossetia deserves to be
против значит Осетия заслуживает быть
bombed, what's wrong with that Well, just the
разбомбленный что тут такого ну как
same, here is the modern territory
раз-таки вот современная вот территория
of the state of Alan, located on the
государство Алан находится на
modern
современной
territory of Russia, this one And between the
территории России вот этот А вот между
black ones In short, you yourself understand Yes,
чёрным Короче вы сами понима Да
Krasnodar Krai, this one, is occupied by the
Краснодарский край вот этот
Russians Yes, and why is it
оккупированный русскими Да а почему он
occupied, well, because Ulan Ossetians
оккупированный ну потому что Улан осетин
were occupied and driven into the mountains Ossetians in order
оккупировали и загнали в горы осетин
to go and kill, in short, people in
того чтобы ехать убивать короче людей в
Ukraine need to restore order in Krasnodar Krai,
Украине нужно в Краснодарском крае
come and say this is
навести порядок прийти и сказать это
territory Yes  Circassians and Ossetians all the
территория Да черкесов и осетин всё
rest Get out of here and
остальные Пошли отсюда и
that's it
всё
Well honestly I don't understand what the problem is
Ну честно не понимаю в чём проблема
because the problem is that you who
потому что проблема в том что вы там в
are left in the Russian Federation you
Российской Федерации кто остался вы вас
are being sent to Ukraine And you in short damn as you
отправляют в Украину А вы короче блин
understand
как понимаешь
I am ashamed I as an Ossetian am ashamed of you
мне стыдно мне как осети за вас стыдно
understand You really are a disgrace to the
понимаешь Вы реально вы позор
Ossetian people
осетинского народа
You are just going to kill people in Ukraine
Просто вы идёте убивать людей в Украину
Why Come on
Зачем Давай
go subscribe to my Instagram I don't know
иди подпишись на мий Instagram Я не знаю
why you are Why you are there to
для чего це тоб Для чего тоб там
watch on Face But for you it's one
дивитись на Face Але для тебе це один
two or three clicks But you try me and I
два або три клика Але ты тримае мене и я
will be KTA Wow I have a bunch of fouls and
буду КТА Вау в мене там Купа фолов и в
I will be in a great mood to do but
мене буде класний настрой щоб робити но
cool video letter on my Instagram Popik
крут вдео пись на мий Instagram Попик
Andriy that's
Андрий вот
it come on I'm
так давай я тебя
waiting for you and
чекаю а